

Stephen McGregor

Technical writer



Kapiti Coast, New Zealand



github.com/WaterSibilantFalling



work@stephen-mcgregor.com



(+64|0)204 135 2650



stephen-dalglish-mcgregor

About me ———

Friendly, clever, educated. Stephen collects information, history books, music and GNU/Linux documentation while trying to watch only the best cinema. Most days he'll mess with his Debian GNU/Linux setup or program ... something. Stephen has sung in many many choirs and, since starting to listen to audiobooks, reads (that is listens to) six or so each month. Lived in Istanbul for nearly a decade, more than a year at a crown research institute (GeoNet, GNS Science), and now looking for another technical writing contract.

Will relocate.

Skills —

I.T. general knowledge

technical writing

writing aesthetics

Perl

C++, C and Assembly

Python

Interests

Complicated systems, taking notes, bringing order to chaos, opportunities.

Experience

Apr'18 - Jul'19 Technical Writer @ GeoNet, GNS Science Seismic Monitoring Produced technical documentation:

- SOPs for GeoNet's 24/7 National Geohazards Monitoring Centre. Interviewed experts company-wide.
- User and support guides for a huge NZ-wide sensor network.
 Analysed & structured technical data.
- Instructions and checklists covering GeoNet's NZ-wide WAN.
 Many SME interviewes.
- CSS-formatted PDFs. Extracted run books from an Atlassian Confluence wiki. Added clarity & consistency.
- Procedures and draft RACI requirements charts for a Nationally Significant Database. Met Public Records Act (2005) criteria.
 Coded Python scripts to:
- · Convert markdown documents into CSS-formatted PDFs.
- Run appropriate conversion programs upon directory changes.
- Extract a wiki (->HTML->markdown->correct markdown)->PDF. An Agile environment. Significant organisational change.

2010-2018 Rewriting & editing @ multiple clients and nationalities editing Rewrote many thousands of technical documents. Negotiated with clients, met their deadlines, complied with their style guides.

<u>Governmental</u>: Presidential documents (130,000 words), govt' press releases, translated regulations.

<u>Legal</u>: Telco's legal statements, legal opinions, drug trial docs (many), industrial sales contracts.

<u>Telecommunications</u>: technical manuals, technical sales materials, nationwide tracking system documentation, technology overviews. <u>IT systems</u>: tender specifications (RFPs), industrial manuals, operating instructions (many), technical publicity materials.

2013 Technical Writer @ Contact Energy SAP migration Wrote parts of the specifications for a major SAP migration.

2008 Technical Writer @ Country Energy (Australia) systems migration Documented a set of major upgrades and virtualizations.

2007-08 Technical Writer @ Alcatel-Lucent telco
In a team, documented Alcatel-Lucent communications hardware.

2006-07 Technical Writer @ EDS/Telecom NZ (now Spark) telcom WebSphere, Genesys IVR system, VoiceXML voice-recognition.

2005-06 Embedded Developer @ MAS Zengrange embedded & telco Assembly & C development for ICs and GPS chips. Full SDLC.

2002-03 Technical Writer @ Link Communications (Australia) telco Wrote 600-page Operators' Guide for continent-wide telco system.

2001 Technical Writer @ National Bank NZ bond trading Trading systems' process instructions, user manuals, diagrams.

1998-2000 B.A. and C++ Developer @ Quality Systems Ltd. C++, ERP Designed & coded an ERP module. Elicited full SDLC analyses.

Samples

My brochure is here and my creative CV here. These and more on github.

A System Manual I wrote is here, and an API, Dev Guide is here. A sample System Guide can viewed here and an IVR / voice recognition as-built I wrote is here. Many examples of my editing and Proofreading can be downloaded from here. A few of my infoviz Visios can be seen here and an art-piece in UML (yes) is here.



Stephen McGregor

Technical writer



Kapiti Coast, New Zealand



github.com/WaterSibilantFalling



work@stephen-mcgregor.com



(+64|0)204 135 2650

stephen-dalglish-mcgregor

About me ———

Friendly, clever, educated. Stephen collects information, history books, music and GNU/Linux documentation while trying to watch only the best cinema. Most days he'll mess with his Debian GNU/Linux setup or program ... something. Stephen has sung in many many choirs and, since starting to listen to audiobooks, reads (that is listens to) six or so each month. Lived in Istanbul for nearly a decade, more than a year at a crown research institute (GeoNet, GNS Science), and now looking for another technical writing contract.

Will relocate.

Skills —

I.T. general knowledge

technical writing

writing aesthetics

Perl

C++, C and Assembly

Python

Education

2005

	ciectionic physics, geomagnetism, mers, bor, hare optics		
2004	post-grad diploma advanced international marketing, tourism, third-w	Otago University orld marketing	
2003	graduate diploma electronic design and systems, microcontrollers, p	Otago University hysics	
1993	B.Sc (Chemistry) chemical engineering, organic chemistry, bio-tech,	Otago University pharmacology	
1990	B.Com (Marketing)	Otago University	

market research / international marketing

electronic physics, geomagnetism, filters, DSP fibre ontics

Victoria University

post-grad electronic physics

Skills

Tech writing Since 2001, mostly manuals for telecommunications & IT. Also APIs, as-builts and banking. A collector & reader of style guides.

Editing Proofread and edited thousands of commercial, technical, IT, legal

and miscellaneous documents. Broad range of clients.

Telecoms Professionally developed a telecoms device. Documented many different telecoms systems. Studied fibre optics at post-grad level.

Embedded Former embedded developer. Used dsPic, Atmel & FPGAs. Grad

Dip(Electronics) and studied post-grad.

Coding Perl 5, C, Python, C++, assembly. Formerly SAS, SPSS. Coding

since 1983 and still coding most days. My Github is here.

Applications Microsoft Office, Inkscape, Visio, Gimp (like Photoshop). Vim. Tra-

dos Studio, Wordfast. Have used MadCap Flare, Adobe InDesign.

Platforms Unix since 1989, Debian GNU/Linux since 2001, Microsoft since

MS-DOS. My first computer was a ZX-81.

Database MySQL, sqlite3, some Oracle. Intermediate-level SQL but very

familiar with databases. Many database-orientated roles.

Commercial Telecoms, heavy industry, finance, defence, utilities, software.

Started own small business. Two business degrees.

Modelling Modelled a \$35m capacity purchase, a \$10m economic project and

for a \$20m legal case. Capacity reporting for Telecom NZ.

Sys Admin Networking, wireless, iptables, security & encryption, udev and

/sys, /proc, kernel stuff, sound and video formats, backups, logs.

Statistical Was a statistical analyst; studied statistics to uni second-year.

Analytical National Network Analyst, BA. An analytical, technical disposition.

Professional Memberships

TechCommNZ Technical Communicators Association of New Zealand Inc Member of NZ's Association for professional technical writers

References

Dr Tatiana Goded

Seismic Hazard Modeller

GNS Science

t.goded@gns.cri.nz +04 570 4029

Dr Jerome Salichon

Seismologist - Earthquake analysis systems specialist

GeoNet; GNS Science

J.Salichon@gns.cri.nz +04 570 4855